ROB WILLIFORD

P Denver, CO

EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer

Freelance

i 10/2022 - 05/2023

Remote - Denver, CO

Various

- Freelance software development for a local enterprise company in Denver
- Worked on the user customer experience team for billing
- C# Xamarin and TypeScript Angular development
- Helped mentor junior developers and presented to department on similarities and differences of C# and TypeScript to help with the facilitation of a technology stack shift for the mobile customer experience - the transition was/is from C# Xamarin to Angular PWA with Ionic
- Work sourced through Unison Systems

Senior Software Engineer

Blackbaud

=== 11/2021 - 10/2022

Remote - Denver, CO

Computer Software Company

- (Full-time) Full-stack, cloud-native software engineering leveraging .NET/Azure (Angular/RxJS front-end, C#/Azure back-end)
- Worked on the accounting side of the next generation, web-based version of the company's Financial Edge software offering
- Performed end to end software implementations for feature enhancements and existing defects from UI to Database systems
- Member of the coding interview working group tasked with refining and improving the algorithms and data structures aspect of the interview experience for prospective software engineering company candidates

Senior Software Engineer

Freelance

= 09/2020 - 10/2021

Remote - Raleigh, NC

Various

- Freelance, full-stack software development consulting on various client
- Industries include freight supply chain, entertainment, healthcare, and energy industries.
- Majority of projects utilize AWS, OpenJDK 8/11, ReactJS, and NodeJS. Work sourced through Vaco LLC and Eliassen Group LLC.

Software Engineer

PrecisionHawk

m 11/2019 - 09/2020

Hybrid - Raleigh, NC

Drone/Software Solutions for Energy and Agriculture

- (Full-time) Full-stack react and Java8/OpenIDK development utilizing an AWS infrastructure.
- The application allows energy companies to monitor the transmission lines and components of their electrical grid infrastructure via drone imaging

Software Engineer

IBM

m 03/2019 - 10/2019

RTP

Cloud, IT, and IoT solutions

- (Full-time) Built automated solutions using Python3 for database data migrations for quote to cash financial information hosted on IBMCloud.
- Worked on building a new cloud-native PaaS with a distributed systems back-end implemented in Go, ReactJS front-ends, and using Kubernetes hosted on IBMCloud.
- Focused on optimizing data-streaming capabilities for file upload/download, and gathering and aggregating associated financial metadata via building internal API integrations with other internal, financial services. (CIO department).

SUMMARY

I'm a full-stack generalist with over 7 years of industry experience interested in fullstack or platform engineering opportunities. I like pushing the boundaries of what people think is possible. I enjoy working on applications that have the potential to shift paradigms, and drive large impact. I value and like to help cultivate empathy and collaboration in a team oriented environment, and am an advocate for work-life balance in company cultures.

SKILLS

Languages



Frameworks



Infrastructure



Cloud

AWS **IBM Cloud Pivotal** Azure **EXPERIENCE PASSIONS**

Software Engineer

= 06/2017 - 03/2019

O Hybrid - RTP

Digital Security and Networking Solutions

- (Contract) Full-stack web development on a web application that assesses the viability of software images to be deployed to production systems by analyzing file contents.
- Led the development on service integrations and page navigation mechanisms, and expanded the functionality of numerous back-end services. Deployed on a hybrid-cloud infrastructure.
- Used: heavy Ruby and JS usage as well as some Go, Java, and Python.

EDUCATION

B.S. Environmental Science/Mathematics

Open Source

Physics/Mathematics

Traveling

Environment